Derek Mahon papers, circa 1948-2008
Emory University
- Legal and financial records, Series 6; Box 47
  This series includes a variety of financial and legal papers, among them royalty statements, contracts, and material regarding rights and permissions.
  Arranged by record type.
  - Contracts (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Contracts (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Legal documents (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Rights and permissions (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Rights and permissions (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Royalty statements (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Royalty statements (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Royalty statements (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Royalty statements (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Royalty statements (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Royalty statements (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Irish Times pay statements (Box 47, Folder 12)
- Subject files, Series 7; Box 48 - Box 50
  The series contains subject files consisting primarily of printed material collected by Derek Mahon (but not by or about him) relating to organizations, events, and individuals.
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - American Irish Historical Society (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Beckett, Samuel (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Betjeman, John (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Book inscriptions (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Clifton, Harry: Aosdána application materials (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Clouds and weather (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Curriculum Vitae and autobiographical notes (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Cyrano de Bergerac (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Edinburgh Book Festival (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Emory University (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Farrell, J. G. (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - GPA Book Award (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Guggenheim Fellowship (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Higgins, Aidan (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Hodgkin, Howard (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Hytner, Nicholas [director of the National Theatre] (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Ireland and its Diaspora (Frankfurt Book Fair 1996) (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - Ireland House (Box 48, Folder 19)
  - Irish Times-Aer Lingus Prize (Box 48, Folder 20)
  - Italy - visits (Box 48, Folder 21)
  - Kinsale Arts Week (Box 48, Folder 22)
  - Lannan Foundation (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Lighthouses (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - MacNeice, Louis (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Madden, Anne (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Mermaid Turbulence [journal] (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Minihan, John (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Minihan, John (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Minihan, John (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Poetry Society of America (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Readings and conference programs (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - St. Patrick's Day (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Shelbourne Hotel (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Society of Authors-Cholmondeley Awards (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Teaching materials (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Titanic (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Unterberg Poetry Center (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Various reproductions of paintings (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - W.B. Yeats International Theatre Festival (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - W.B. Yeats Society (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - William Scott (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Yaddo (Box 50, Folder 10)
- Ephemera, Series 8; Box 51 - 52; OP12-16
  The series contains ephemera including membership cards, address books, airplane tickets, and Mahon's degree from the University of Dublin.
  - Address books (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Address book, circa 2001 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Addresses, various (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Art: Greacen, Lavinia, "Bedspring Art," with accompanying note by DM (Box OP12)
  - Art: Journeaux, Hammond, charcoal drawings of Derek Mahon's hands, August 2001 (Box OP13)
  - Art: Journeaux, Hammond, painting of J.P. Donleavy, 2004-2005 (Box OP14)
  - Business cards (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Children's artwork (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Children's artwork (Box OP15)
  - David Cohen Prize for Literature 2007, dinner menu (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Membership cards (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - National University of Ireland, conferral of Honorary Degree, 29 June 2001 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Passport (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Personal papers (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Student evaluations [Barnard College] (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Tickets, travel (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Tickets, travel (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Tickets, various (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Tickets, various (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - University of Dublin, degree (Box OP16)
  - Fleur Fitzgerald, fragments of clay sculpture of Derek Mahon (Box 52, Folder 1)
- Collected materials, Series 9; Box 53
  The collected materials located in Series 9 include correspondence and other material acquired from various sources. For details regarding the provenance of specific items in this artificially assembled portion of the collection, consult the library staff.
  Arranged by accession.
  - Glyn Hughes correspondence, circa 1970s and 1980s (Accession 2008-06-40)
  - Correspondence: Derek Mahon to Glyn Hughes, circa 1970s, 1980 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Writings: "Fire-King," MS (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Writings: "Runes," TS (Box 53, Folder 3)
- Unprocessed additions, Series 10; Boxes 54 - 59
  Series 10 is closed to researchers.
  - Correspondence [RESTRICTED] (Box 54)
  - Mixed files [RESTRICTED] (Box 55)
  - Unprocessed additions [acc. 2011-05-07] [RESTRICTED] (Box 56)
  - Unprocessed additions [acc. 2011-05-07] [RESTRICTED] (Box 57)
  - Mixed files [RESTRICTED] (Box 58)
  - Correspondence [RESTRICTED] (Box 59)